<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<analysisEngineDescription xmlns="http://uima.apache.org/resourceSpecifier">
    <frameworkImplementation>org.apache.uima.java</frameworkImplementation>
    <primitive>true</primitive>
    <annotatorImplementationName>de.julielab.jcore.multiplier.gnp.GNormPlusXMLDBMultiplier</annotatorImplementationName>
    <analysisEngineMetaData>
        <name>JCoRe GNormPlus XML Database Multiplier</name>
        <description>A CAS multiplier to be used with the DB XML multiplier reader in place of the DB XML multiplier. It wraps the JULIE Lab variant of the GNormPlus gene ID mapper. It is a multiplier because this enables batch-processing of documents with GNormPlus which makes the processing more efficient.</description>
        <version>2.6.1</version>
        <vendor>JULIE Lab Jena, Germany</vendor>
        <configurationParameters>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>UseExistingGeneAnnotations</name>
                <description>If set to true, all Gene annotations in the CAS will be added to the BioC documents. The default type used is de.julielab.jcore.types.Gene. This can be changed with the InputGeneTypeName parameter.</description>
                <type>Boolean</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>OutputGeneTypeName</name>
                <description>The UIMA type denoting gene annotations that should be created by this component. Must by a sub type of de.julielab.jcore.types.ConceptMention. Defaults to de.julielab.jcore.types.Gene.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>GNormPlusSetupFile</name>
                <description>File path or class path resource path to the setup.txt file for GNormPlus. If not specified, a default setup file is loaded that expects the Dictionary/ directory directly under the working directory, performs gene recognition with the CRF and thus expects the GNormPlus CRF directory directly under the working directory and maps the found genes to NCBI gene IDs for all organisms.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>InputGeneTypeName</name>
                <description>The UIMA type denoting gene annotations that should be taken from the CAS and written into the BioC format for GNormPlus to use instead of running its own gene recognition when the UseExistingGeneAnnotations parameter is set to true.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>OutputDirectory</name>
                <description>Optional. If specified, the GNormPlus output files in BioC format will be saved to the given directory. In this way, this component can be used directly as a BioC XML writer through the GNormPlus algorithm.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>FocusSpecies</name>
                <description>If given, all gene mentions are assigned to this NCBI taxonomy ID, i.e. species recognition is omitted.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>SkipUnchangedDocuments</name>
                <description>Whether to omit GNormPlus processing on documents that already exist in the XMI database table and whose document text has not changed.</description>
                <type>Boolean</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>RowMapping</name>
                <description>In case that the CoStoSys active table schema specified more than two columns to be retrieved, the other columns need a mapping into the CAS.A mapping item has the following form: &lt;column index&gt;=&lt;uima type&gt;#&lt;type feature&gt;:&lt;feature datatype&gt;:defaultValue where the defaultValue is optional. Example: 2=de.julielab.jules.types.max_xmi_id#id:int:0 maps the content of the third (index 2, zero-based) retrieved column (may also belong to an additional table!) to feature "id" of the type "d.j.j.t.max_xmi_id" which is an int. In case there is no value returned from the database for a document, use a 0 as default.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>true</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>MappingFile</name>
                <description>An XML mapping file following the specification required by the jcore-xml-mapper. The mapping file specifies how contents from an XML docuent are to be brought into the CAS.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>true</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>AddShaHash</name>
                <description>For use with AnnotationDefinedFlowController and XMIDBWriter. Possible values: document_text, defaults to 'document_text' and thus doesn't need to be specified manually at the moment. This parameter needs to match the value for the same parameter given to the XMIDBWriter in this pipeline. Then, a comparison between the existing hash in the database and the new hash of the CAS read in this pipeline can be made. In case the hashes match, the CAS is directly routed to the components specified in the ToVisitKeys parameter, skipping all other components. Note that this only works with AAEs where the first component is an 'AnnotationControlledFlow'. Additionally, the DBProcessingMetaData#hasDocumentHashChanged is set. This can be used by the XMIDBWriter to omit the reset of mirror subsets when updating the base document when the actual CAS text stayed the same.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>DocumentTable</name>
                <description>For use with AnnotationDefinedFlowController. String parameter indicating the name of the table where the XMI data and, thus, the hash is stored. The name must be schema qualified. Note that in this component, only the ToVisit annotation is created that determines which components to apply to a CAS with matching (unchanged) hash. The logic to actually control the CAS flow is contained in the AnnotationDefinedFlowController.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>DocumentTableSchema</name>
                <description>For use with AnnotationDefinedFlowController. The name of the schema that the document table - given with the DocumentTable parameter - adheres to. Only the primary key part is required for hash value retrieval.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>ToVisitKeys</name>
                <description>For use with AnnotationDefinedFlowController. Specifies the delegate AE keys of the AEs this CAS should still applied on although the hash has not changed. Can be null or empty indicating that no component should be applied to the CAS. The task of the AnnotationDefinedFlowController is then to read those annotations and route the CAS accordingly.</description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>true</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>AddToVisitKeys</name>
                <description>Toggles the creation of annotations for the AnnotationDefinedFlowController. Only needed when such a flow controller is used in the pipeline. For details, see the description of ToVisitKeys.</description>
                <type>Boolean</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>AddUnchangedDocumentTextFlag</name>
                <description>Toggles the addition of the 'document text is unchanged' flag. The value of this flag is determined via a SHA256 hash of the CAS document text. When DocumentTable and DocumentTableSchema are specified, the hash value of the document in storage is retrieved and compared to the current value. The flag is then set with respect to the comparison result.</description>
                <type>Boolean</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>TruncateAtSize</name>
                <description>Specify size in bytes of the XML document size. If the document surpasses that size, it is not populated from XMI but given some placeholder information. This can be necessary when large documents cannot be handled by subsequent components in the pipeline.</description>
                <type>Integer</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
        </configurationParameters>
        <configurationParameterSettings>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>UseExistingGeneAnnotations</name>
                <value>
                    <boolean>false</boolean>
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>OutputGeneTypeName</name>
                <value>
                    <string>de.julielab.jcore.types.Gene</string>
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>InputGeneTypeName</name>
                <value>
                    <string>de.julielab.jcore.types.Gene</string>
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
        </configurationParameterSettings>
        <typeSystemDescription>
            <imports>
                <import name="de.julielab.jcore.types.jcore-document-structure-pubmed-types" />
                <import name="de.julielab.jcore.types.jcore-semantics-biology-types" />
                <import name="de.julielab.jcore.types.jcore-document-meta-pubmed-types" />
                <import name="de.julielab.jcore.types.extensions.jcore-document-meta-extension-types" />
                <import name="de.julielab.jcore.types.jcore-casflow-types" />
            </imports>
        </typeSystemDescription>
        <fsIndexCollection />
        <capabilities>
            <capability>
                <inputs />
                <outputs>
                    <type>de.julielab.jcore.types.ConceptMention</type>
                    <type>de.julielab.jcore.types.Organism</type>
                </outputs>
                <languagesSupported />
            </capability>
        </capabilities>
        <operationalProperties>
            <modifiesCas>true</modifiesCas>
            <multipleDeploymentAllowed>true</multipleDeploymentAllowed>
            <outputsNewCASes>true</outputsNewCASes>
        </operationalProperties>
    </analysisEngineMetaData>
</analysisEngineDescription>