<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<collectionReaderDescription xmlns="http://uima.apache.org/resourceSpecifier">
    <frameworkImplementation>org.apache.uima.java</frameworkImplementation>
    <implementationName>de.julielab.jcore.reader.db.DBMultiplierReader</implementationName>
    <processingResourceMetaData>
        <name>JCoRe Database Multiplier Reader</name>
        <description>A collection reader that receives the IDs of documents from a database table. Additional tables may
            be specified which will, together with the IDs, be sent to a CAS multiplier extendingthe DBMultiplierReader.
            The multiplier will read documents and the joined additional tables according to the list of document IDs
            sent by this reader. The component leverages the corpus storage system (CoStoSys) for this purpose and is
            part of the Jena Document Information System, JeDIS.
        </description>
        <version>2.6.0</version>
        <configurationParameters>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>ResetTable</name>
                <description>If set to true and the parameter 'Table' is set to a subset table, the subset table will be
                    reset atthe initialization of the reader to be ready for processing of the whole subset. Do not use
                    when multiple readers read the same subset table.
                </description>
                <type>Boolean</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>Timestamp</name>
                <description>PostgreSQL timestamp expression that is evaluated against the data table. The data table
                    schema, which must be the active data table schema in the CoStoSys configuration as always, must
                    specify a single timestamp field for this parameter to work. Only data rows with a timestamp value
                    larger than the given timestamp expression will be processed. Note that when reading from a subset
                    table, there may be subset rows indicated to be in process which are finally not read from the data
                    table. This is an implementational shortcoming and might be addressed if respective feature requests
                    are given through the JULIE Lab GitHub page or JCoRe issues.
                </description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>FetchIdsProactively</name>
                <description>If set to true and when reading from a subset table, batches of document IDs will be
                    retrieved in a background thread while the previous batch is already in process. This is meant to
                    minimize waiting time for the database. Deactivate this feature if you encounter issues with
                    databaase connections.
                </description>
                <type>Boolean</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>true</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>AdditionalTables</name>
                <description>An array of table names. By default, the table names will be resolved against the active
                    data postgres schema configured in the CoStoSys configuration file. If a name is already schema
                    qualified, i.e. contains a dot, the active data schema will be ignored. When reading documents from
                    the document data table, the additional tables will be joined onto the data table using the primary
                    keys of the queried documents. Using the table schema for the additional documents defined by the
                    'AdditionalTableSchema' parameter, the columns that are marked as 'retrieve=true' in the table
                    schema, are returned together with the main document data. This mechanism is most prominently used
                    to retrieve annotation table data together with the original document text in XMI format for the
                    JeDIS system.
                </description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>true</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>AdditionalTableSchemas</name>
                <description>The table schemas that corresponds to the additional tables given with the
                    'AdditionalTables' parameter. If only one schema name is given, that schema must apply to all
                    additional tables.
                </description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>true</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>BatchSize</name>
                <description />
                <type>Integer</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>true</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>DBDriver</name>
                <description>Currently unused because the Hikari JDBC library should recognize the correct driver.
                    However, there seem to be cases where this doesn't work (HSQLDB). So we keep the parameter for
                    later. When this issue comes up, the driver would have to be set manually. This isn't done right
                    now.
                </description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>Table</name>
                <description>The data or subset database table to read from. The name will be resolved against the
                    active Postgres schema defined in the CoStoSys configuration file.However, if the name contains a
                    schema qualification (i.e. 'schemaname.tablename), the configuration file will be ignored in this
                    point.
                </description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>true</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>SelectionOrder</name>
                <description>WARNING: Potential SQL injection vulnerability. Do not let unknown users interact with your
                    database with this component. An SQL ORDER clause specifying in which order the documents in the
                    target database table should be processed. Only the clause itself must be specified, the ORDER
                    keyword is automatically added.
                </description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>WhereCondition</name>
                <description>WARNING: Potential SQL injection vulnerability. Do not let unknown users interact with your
                    database with this component. Only used when reading data tables directly. No effect when the
                    'tableName' parameter specifies a subset table. The parameter value should be an SQL WHERE clause
                    restricting the documents to be read. Only the clause itself must be specified, the WHERE keyword is
                    added automatically.
                </description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>Limit</name>
                <description />
                <type>Integer</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>false</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
            <configurationParameter>
                <name>CostosysConfigFile</name>
                <description>File path or classpath resource location to the CoStoSys XML configuration. This
                    configuration must specify the table schema of the table referred to by the 'Table' parameter as
                    active table schema. The active table schema is always the schema of the data table that is either
                    queried directly for documents or, if 'tableName' points to a subset table, indirectly through the
                    subset table. Make also sure that the active database connection in the configuration points to the
                    correct database.
                </description>
                <type>String</type>
                <multiValued>false</multiValued>
                <mandatory>true</mandatory>
            </configurationParameter>
        </configurationParameters>
        <configurationParameterSettings>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>ResetTable</name>
                <value>
                    <boolean>false</boolean>
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>FetchIdsProactively</name>
                <value>
                    <boolean>true</boolean>
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>BatchSize</name>
                <value>
                    <integer>100</integer>
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
            <nameValuePair>
                <name>SelectionOrder</name>
                <value>
                    <string />
                </value>
            </nameValuePair>
        </configurationParameterSettings>
        <typeSystemDescription>
            <imports>
                <import name="de.julielab.jcore.types.casmultiplier.jcore-dbtable-multiplier-types" />
            </imports>
        </typeSystemDescription>
        <fsIndexCollection />
        <capabilities />
        <operationalProperties>
            <modifiesCas>true</modifiesCas>
            <multipleDeploymentAllowed>false</multipleDeploymentAllowed>
            <outputsNewCASes>true</outputsNewCASes>
        </operationalProperties>
    </processingResourceMetaData>
</collectionReaderDescription>