<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<typeSystemDescription xmlns="http://uima.apache.org/resourceSpecifier">
    <name>JCoRe File Multiplier Types</name>
    <description>This is a type system for usage with a CAS multiplier. It should not be included into the
        jcore-all-types type system. This particular type system holds a array containing strings that represent the IDs
        of documents to read from database tables. Using an array is used to read batches of document which make
        database access more efficient, for example. Since the primary keys of database tables may have multiple
        elements, a document ID is represented as a StringArray. Multiple tables may be specified in which case
        the tables should be joined on the given document primary keys. This mechanism may be used to read a
        base document and annotations that have been previously created and stored in separate tables. This is
        part of the Jena Document Information System, JeDIS.
    </description>
    <version>2.4.0</version>
    <vendor>JULIE Lab Jena, Germany</vendor>
    <types>
        <typeDescription>
            <name>de.julielab.jcore.types.casmultiplier.RowBatch</name>
            <description>A batch of rows of a database table. An array of identifier strings denotes a documents.
                The name of the table to retrieve the IDs from is another feature of this type. The CAS multiplier
                receiving instances of this type must have access to the correct database.
            </description>
            <supertypeName>uima.tcas.Annotation</supertypeName>
            <features>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>identifiers</name>
                    <description>The document IDs to be read by the CAS multiplier.</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.FSArray</rangeTypeName>
                    <elementType>uima.cas.StringArray</elementType>
                </featureDescription>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>tableName</name>
                    <description>The name of the table that was specified in the reader's descriptor.</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.String</rangeTypeName>
                </featureDescription>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>tables</name>
                    <description>The tables to read the given IDs from. The first element is always the primary data table.
                        If there is more than one array entry, the
                        additional tables are joined by primary key to the first table.
                        The additional tables might hold annotations segmented away
                        from the base document, for example.</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.StringArray</rangeTypeName>
                </featureDescription>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>tableSchemas</name>
                    <description>The CoStoSys table schemas of the tables to read.</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.StringArray</rangeTypeName>
                </featureDescription>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>costosysConfiguration</name>
                    <description>The CoStoSys configuration file path or classpath location.</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.String</rangeTypeName>
                </featureDescription>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>readsBaseXmiDocument</name>
                    <description>Only for XMI DB readers. Specifies whether the JeDIS annotation module base XMI document is read (feature set to true) or a complete, unmodularized XMI document (set to false).</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Boolean</rangeTypeName>
                </featureDescription>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>xmiAnnotationModuleNames</name>
                    <description>Only for XMI DB readers. Lists the Java names of the annotation types whose annotations should be read.</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.StringArray</rangeTypeName>
                </featureDescription>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>storeMaxXmiId</name>
                    <description>Only for XMI DB readers. Specifies whether the documents' max XMI ID should be stored in the multiplier CAS. Necessary for the use with the jcore-xmi-db-consumer.</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Boolean</rangeTypeName>
                </featureDescription>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>increasedAttributeSize</name>
                    <description>For the XMI splitter. Specifies the maximum attribute size the XML parser accepts. Necessary for large texts.</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Integer</rangeTypeName>
                </featureDescription>
                <featureDescription>
                    <name>xercesAttributeBufferSize</name>
                    <description>For the XMI splitter. Allows to increase the internal buffer of the Xerces parser used for attribute values.</description>
                    <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Integer</rangeTypeName>
                </featureDescription>
            </features>
        </typeDescription>
    </types>
</typeSystemDescription>