<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<typeSystemDescription xmlns="http://uima.apache.org/resourceSpecifier">
  <name>JCoRe Discourse Types</name>
  <description>Discourse types such as coreference relations.</description>
  <version>2.6.0-SNAPSHOT</version>
        <vendor>JULIE Lab Jena, Germany</vendor>
  <imports>
    <import location="jcore-basic-types.xml" />
    <import location="jcore-semantics-mention-types.xml" />
  </imports>
  <types>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>de.julielab.jcore.types.CorefRelation</name>
      <description>A coreference relation connecting one anaphor to one or multiple antecedents this anaphor is referring to.</description>
      <supertypeName>de.julielab.jcore.types.Annotation</supertypeName>
      <features>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>antecedents</name>
          <description>The coreference expressions referred to by the anaphor of this coreference relation.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.FSArray</rangeTypeName>
          <elementType>de.julielab.jcore.types.CorefExpression</elementType>
        </featureDescription>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>id</name>
          <description />
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.String</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>anaphora</name>
          <description>The anaphora that refers to other corefence expression as antecedents in this coreference relation.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>de.julielab.jcore.types.CorefExpression</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
      </features>
    </typeDescription>
    <typeDescription>
      <name>de.julielab.jcore.types.CorefExpression</name>
      <description>A 'coreference expression' might be any span of text that is part of a set of text expressions referring to the same entity. Speaking in the anaphora framework, co-reference expressions are either anaphors - mostly pronouns and definite noun phrases - or their antecedents - the original, first mention of an entity or already an anaphoric expression referring itself to a reference to the original entity mention.</description>
      <supertypeName>de.julielab.jcore.types.Annotation</supertypeName>
      <features>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>isAnaphor</name>
          <description>Whether this coreference expression is an anaphor, i.e. a textual expression referring to another entity expression earlier in the text.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Boolean</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>isAntecedent</name>
          <description>Whether this coreference expression is an antecedent to one or more anaphora expressions later in the text.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.Boolean</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>antecedentRelation</name>
          <description>The actual relations TO antecedents of THIS expression. I.e. if there is at least one coreference relation found at this feature, this coreference expression is automatically an anaphor. Note that it can also be an antecedent to other anaphors.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>de.julielab.jcore.types.CorefRelation</rangeTypeName>
        </featureDescription>
        <featureDescription>
          <name>anaphoraRelations</name>
          <description>The actual relations TO anaphors of THIS expression. I.e. if there is at least one coreference relation found at this feature, this coreference expression is automatically an antecedent to at least one anaphor found later in the text. Note that it can also be a an anaphor at the same time.</description>
          <rangeTypeName>uima.cas.FSArray</rangeTypeName>
          <elementType>de.julielab.jcore.types.CorefRelation</elementType>
        </featureDescription>
      </features>
    </typeDescription>
  </types>
</typeSystemDescription>